Stephan Kostov

stephank179@gmail.com ❖ (+44) 7446903000 ❖ github.com/stephankostov ❖ Edinburgh, Scotland

A diligent and forward-thinking team-player with a comprehensive set of problem-solving and analytical skills. These were developed through experience in engineering both software and mechanical, along with a core data skillset through an MSc in Data Analytics. Most recently I've had the opportunity to take a sabbatical break from work to build competence in all things AI through courses, textbooks, and AI-agent development projects. With these skills I am now wholeheartedly committed to contribute in the fascinating and exciting field of AI.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sky Group Ltd

April. 2021 – December 2022

DevOps Engineer

Livingston, Scotland

I was the DevOps engineer of the scrum team responsible for managing the deployments and infrastructure around the development team's services. In addition to these responsibilities I also completed a development project of creating an assistant chatbot for the platform's DevOps services from the ground up in Node.js.

- DevOps infrastructure responsibilities:
 - o Service Deployment
 - Containerised (Kubernetes) Docker Images
 - Legacy (Linux)
 - o Performance Metrics (InfluxDB)
 - o Metrics Dashboards (Grafana)

- o Message Queues (Apache Kafka)
- o Log storage (ElasticSearch)
- o CI/CD Deployment Pipelines (Jenkins & Gitlab)
- o Server Setup (Unix & Windows)
- Developed internal platform-wide Microsoft Teams and Slack chatbot application, serving as a core platform to add automations for support requests. This was built from scratch in Node.js following test-driven-development and functional programming paradigms.

Hong Kong Polytechnic University (IAESTE Internship Program)

June 2020 – August 2020

Aeronautical Engineering Intern

Hong Kong

- Assisting a research team in investigating aerofoils by computationally simulating their physical hydro-tunnel experiments for use in an academic paper.
- Presentation of internship experience to colleagues, university board members, and internship program staff.

EDUCATION

University of Glasgow

September 2020 - June, 2021

MSc Data Analytics (1st Class)

Glasgow, Scotland

- Relevant Classes: Statistics, Bayesian Statistics, Probability, Data Analysis, Deep Learning for Big Data, Machine Learning, Application Development.
- Project: Dissertation in "Predicting Astrophysical Properties of Stars" through Statistical and Machine Learning modelling.

University of Strathclyde

September 2015 - May, 2020

BEng Mechanical Engineering (1st Class)

Glasgow, Scotland

- Core Projects:
 - o Dissertation in "Optimising Space Flight Trajectories" through an exploration and tuning of the state-of-the-art computation optimisation algorithms.
 - o Design and Manufacturing of a model drag racer car in a team of 5.
- Competing in the University Men's Basketball 1st team (division 1).

ADDITIONAL COURSES AND LEARNING

FastAI: Practical Deep Learning Foundations

February 2023 - May 2023

- o Course on the foundations of deep learning, and the state-of-the-art models.
- FDM Software Development Graduate Program

November 2020 - April 2021

o Training course in full-stack OOP with Spring Boot Java and React, also including separate weeks for each SQL, Python, and Unix.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming: Python, Javascript, Bash, HTML/CSS, R, Java, Groovy, MATLAB
- Deep Learning: PyTorch, NumPy
- Data Visualisation: Matplotlib, Pandas, R, Grafana
- Statistics: Regression, Classification, Clustering
- Web Development: React, Spring Boot
- Technologies: Unix, Jenkins, Docker, Kubernetes, Kafka, ElasticSearch, Azure
- Databases: Oracle SQL, InfluxDB, MongoDB

INTERESTS

Basketball, Rock Climbing, Videogames, Piano, Reading, Cooking, Skiing, Travel